Sunaina Bidurga Shashikumar

Chicago, IL - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Sunaina-Bidurga-Shashikumar/2e8dc27f901bd8f7

A dynamic professional with close to 2 years of work experience and currently pursuing Master's degree in Computer Science.

Possess strong understanding and experience on Data Mining and Data Analytics with R, Data Science, Machine Learning,

programming languages and Database management.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Engineer

Hewlett Packard - Bangalore, Karnataka - April 2014 to July 2016

- Provided technical support for infrastructure and applications to E.ON, an UK based energy company.
- Provided onsite and offsite troubleshooting assistance and have trained clients on effective use of applications
- Trained and groomed new team members on relevant technologies and domain.

Associate Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd - Chennai, Tamil Nadu - July 2014 to May 2015

- Implementation and maintenance of network, application, and database servers.
- Used tools called SCOM and HPNNMi to monitor the servers and networks.
- Network devices Cisco routers, switches, implementation, and maintenance & operations.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Engineering

Illinois Institute of Technology - Chicago, IL 2016 to 2018

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science and Engineering

Vishveshwarya Institute of Engineering and Technology -Bapuji Institute of Engineering and Technology 2010 to 2014

SKILLS

DATABASE (3 years), DATABASE MANAGEMENT (3 years), JAVA (3 years), MYSQL (3 years), DATA ANALYTICS (1 year), HTML (3 years), CSS, Javascript (2 years)

AWARDS

Best Performer Award

February 2016

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming and Scripting Business Intelligence Concepts

Python, R, Java, C and C++, HTML and CSS Data Analytics, Data Mining and Machine Learning Database Management Systems Tools

Oracle, MS SQL and MySQL Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power BI, Visio, Google sheets and MPP